{
    "id": "04640b035b8b4f3aae8c9029a43db2c5",
    "title": "Simple, Complex Or Compound Sentence",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We met rather few people who spoke English.",
            "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adjective clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9826c10db4c34002af025f47533bb505"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have been on rather too many planes and trains recently.",
            "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence it has only one clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b9772840c2b5429bae2f9edd7f7a1e2c"
        },
        {
            "question": "We drove right up to Helsinki in two days.",
            "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence it has only one clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3dec51f4dd1f446488f25bace41e92d6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t care how expensive it is.",
            "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate noun clause which acts as the object of the verb ‘don’t care’.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "243c24935a6b4f3c805b3eef54c8ec75"
        },
        {
            "question": "Two minutes ago the child was fast asleep, but now he is wide awake.",
            "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the conjunction but.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1ab30ce647ec446fbe0516b422403585"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is not tall enough to be a soldier.",
            "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence it has only one clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c1285fc7ee68428fb6aa0229e341db52"
        },
        {
            "question": "I guess she just doesn’t respect you.",
            "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate noun clause which acts as the object of the verb ‘guess’.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d8b5c81481114a20803ade067db3fdb4"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have got four sisters and each of them is quite different from the others.",
            "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the conjunction and.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e9846c31688146ad9a51a4d7578b0a3f"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can either come with me now or walk home.",
            "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the conjunction either…or.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "46d9a444c79448969a1ce61f8a0812b7"
        },
        {
            "question": "He will never leave home because he hasn’t got the courage to.",
            "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adverb clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "933fa46e4f534e2f9c00f437e7cf0373"
        },
        {
            "question": "When all else fails, read the user manual.",
            "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adverb clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "66afd113cf2c4623a765a609895ad9d3"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was Sam who paid for the drinks.",
            "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adjective clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple sentence",
                "Complex sentence",
                "Compound sentence"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "25c6091ab70a413aabea3b63d675edb6"
        }
    ]
}